Guide to the Fifth Avenue Coach Company Collection 1895-1962 PR 18
New-York Historical Society
- Series X: Albums and Scrapbooks
  The advertisements, which are clipped from a number of different publications and are directed either at riders, potential advertisers, or potential purchasers of coaches, make liberal use of the exterior and interior views of coaches found in Series I. In most cases, the price the company paid for each ad is penciled at the top.
  Everybody's Motor Car, the photographs and clippings album, was most likely compiled in the late 1910s. It contains photographs with extensive typed and handwritten captions that promote a positive image of the company, touting its fine facilities and the excellent construction of its buses, the high rates of employee and customer satisfaction, its impressive safety record, and its patriotic endeavors in wartime. It is divided into the following sections: Company History, The Company and Its Employees, and The Company and the Public. The photographs in this album are for the most part duplicates of items found in Series I, Series III, and Series VI, picturing coaches, employees at work and at leisure, and wartime activities. Together with the photographs are printed materials, including the February 1917 issue of Bus Lines, the Fifth Avenue Coach Association Membership Book, an instruction book for employees, another copy of Motor Bus Relief for New York's Transit Needs, a Central Park Guide, maps, and advertisements clipped from other publications.
  The photographs in the small album feature several views from the 1920s of the interior, exterior, chassis, and engine parts of types J, L, and 2L coaches, as well as curves charting their horse power, engine performance, and speed. The majority of these images are duplicates of items found in Series I and VII. Though it contains no captions, this album may have been used to visually demonstrate the features and craftsmanship of these particular coaches to potential purchasers.
  - Large Scrapbook, 1911-1922 (Offsite-box 15, Folder unknown container)
  - Loose clippings from Scrapbook, 1911-1922 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 93)
  - Small Photograph Album, undated (Offsite-box 16, Folder 94)
  - Clippings and Photograph Album (disbound), 1895-1918 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 94)